<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


 <LanguageData>

  <LetterLabelDeathclawPasses>Deathclaw is roaming nearby!</LetterLabelDeathclawPasses>
  <LetterDeathclawPasses>This creature is also known as the "Living Nightmare of the Wasteland". Its claws are coveted prey for madmen who believe they can outsmart death.\n\nAt first glance, the Deathclaw appears to be just a giant lizard, but the Wasteland loves dark jokes. Its camouflage is flawless, and its killing speed is faster than your ability to realize you're already dead.\n\nDesperate hunters sometimes try to tame it, but it most often ends with their last words, "It can't see me..." remaining unanswered. Those who miraculously manage to tame this monster don't get a pet, but a personal executioner with a very specific sense of humor.</LetterDeathclawPasses>

  <LetterLabelStrangeDutenPasses>Strange Duten is roaming nearby!</LetterLabelStrangeDutenPasses>
  <LetterStrangeDutenPasses>In a world where radiation has turned cockroaches into dog-sized creatures and mosquitoes into personal helicopters of death, this mutant has managed to outdo them all. Meet the Strange Duten - an insect so huge that its shadow covers entire settlements, so vicious that even super mutants check if the door is locked, and so resilient that it will survive nuclear winter, your headshot, and the very concept of hope.\n\nOnce this was an ordinary duten - well, if you consider a stool-sized creature that feeds on radiation and human fear "ordinary". But after it devoured a warehouse of experimental stimulants, a couple of energy cells, and, according to rumors, an Enclave scientist (well, protein is protein), evolution decided to joke. Now it's a flying tank with wings that:\n• Glows so brightly it could serve as a beacon for ships (if there were any ships left in the Wasteland);\n• Buzzes louder than a crashed helicopter engine (and breaks down about as often);\n• Attacks with everything it has: stinger, claws, acid, plasma, and pure, unadulterated hatred.\n\nWhy hasn't it been killed yet?\nGood question. Bounty hunters tried - their last words were usually, "I'll just get my shotgun... OW". Raiders tried to tame it - now their base looks like a buffet. Even the Brotherhood of Steel once sent a squad after it - they returned without a paladin but with new phobias.</LetterStrangeDutenPasses>

  <LetterLabelHugeBeeArrived>Giant bees are circling nearby!</LetterLabelHugeBeeArrived>
  <HugeBeeArrived>Genetic experiments, radiation, and the cosmic mockery of nature have led to these striped horrors no longer just pollinating flowers - they systematically destroy everything that dared to evolve without their permission. Their buzzing isn't a sound, it's a mockery of your pathetic attempts to survive. They build their hives from the wreckage of your homes, their larvae feed on your hopes, and their venom dissolves not only flesh but the very desire to resist.\n\nThey're faster than your bullets, smarter than your traps, and angrier than a hungry super mutant with a hangover. While you hide in your bunker, they've already stolen your supplies, pollinated your garden (now something with teeth grows there), and set up your dog with their drone. Congratulations - in a week you'll either have a new mutated pet or some very scary memories.\n\nThe only way to fight them is complete destruction. With fire, acid, or a nuclear charge (the latter, by the way, only excites them more). Or just accept it - soon your tombstone will bear the inscription: "Here lies [YOUR NAME]. Posthumously pollinated."</HugeBeeArrived>

  <LetterLabelDuten>Duten are circling nearby!</LetterLabelDuten>
  <DutenArrived>This marvel of mutation - probably a descendant of a horsefly or botfly - has perfected the most disgusting survival strategy in nature. The Wasteland's answer to overpopulation.\n\nReproduction? Oh, it's efficient. Forget mating dances - this creature fires live larvae like biological artillery. One hit - and congratulations! Now you're a walking incubator. (Pro tip: fire helps a lot with... the brood situation.)\n\nApproach with caution - or better yet, with a flamethrower. Their idea of "family bonds" includes turning your chest cavity into a nursery.\n\n"Circle of life, they said. Beautiful, they said. LIARS" - the last words of a Wasteland "bee enthusiast".</DutenArrived>

  <ShockDesc>Radroach shorted something in the generator</ShockDesc>
  <ShockLabel>Electric Shock!</ShockLabel>

  <LetterLabelWatcher>"Watcher 011" has spared your settlement... For now</LetterLabelWatcher>
  <WatcherProtection>You were stuck in the usual post-apocalyptic mess - raiders at the gates, crops dying, settlers whining about a "radroach invasion" as if the world hadn't already ended - when it happened. The air grew thick. Static charge grated in your teeth. Shadows stretched unnaturally, as if reality itself was holding its breath.\n\nAnd then... nothing.\nNo raider attacks. No mutated creatures chewing on the walls. No sudden radiation storm turning your brahmin into glowing mutants. Only... silence. Unnatural. Disturbing. The kind that makes even local drug addicts freeze with a needle in their vein and mutter, "This ain't right."\n\nTurns out, Watcher 011 was just passing by.\n\nYou didn't see it - of course, no one ever does. But you felt it - that nasty sensation of being examined, weighed, and deemed... worthy of attention for now. Maybe it pitied you. Maybe your suffering seemed amusing to it. Or maybe it needs your settlement to remain intact for some incomprehensible cosmic joke.\n\nBut here's the catch:\nYour food supplies are untouched (Incredibly).\nYour turrets haven't fired a single shot (Suspiciously).\nYour settlers are alive (Which, frankly, is disappointing).\nBut don't celebrate too soon. Watchers don't help. They observe. And sooner or later they always return - usually right when everything is about to go to hell.\n\nSo enjoy the lull while it lasts. And maybe start stockpiling flamethrowers. Just in case.\n\n"You're always welcome"</WatcherProtection>

  <LetterLabelCargoPodWatcher>"Watcher 011" just dropped something.</LetterLabelCargoPodWatcher>
  <CargoPodWatcher>Maybe it was an experiment. Maybe an act of mercy - if such beings even have such a concept. Or maybe it just dropped this while passing by, like a person dropping crumbs without noticing the ants.\n\nBut here's the catch:\nWatchers don't help. They observe.\nAnd if they brought something... it means they need you to use it for some reason.\n\nSo celebrate. Stock up. Fortify.\nAnd wait.\nBecause they always return - usually right when their "gift" turns out to be the final piece of the puzzle in someone's incomprehensible game.\n\nIn the meantime... maybe check these gifts for hidden traps?\nJust in case.</CargoPodWatcher>

  <RadroachEatersLabel>Radroach Infestation.</RadroachEatersLabel>
  <RadroachEatersDesc>Filth, mess, and typical post-apocalyptic squalor have led to these radioactive critters evolving - and now they're not just eating your pathetic vegetables, but also mocking you. Yes, their chirping isn't just a sound, but genuine mocking commentary about your worthless life. They breed faster than your settlers die, their shells are tougher than your will to live, and their bites leave behind not only rotting flesh but a deep sense of humiliation.\n\nAnd the scariest part? They're smarter than you. While you're digging in the dirt looking for food, they've already stolen your supplies, eaten your dog, and left a radioactive "gift" on your bed. Congratulations, now you have either diarrhea or a mutation. Or maybe both.\n\nThe only way to get rid of them is fire. Lots of fire. Or just accept it and acknowledge that this is their world now, and you're just a temporary food source in it.</RadroachEatersDesc>

  <LetterLabelGlowRadDeerPasses>Quantum Rad Deer Appearance</LetterLabelGlowRadDeerPasses>
  <LetterGlowRadDeerPasses>The Wasteland is getting brighter - a Quantum Rad Deer has been spotted in the vicinity. These unique creatures appeared as a result of ordinary rad deer mutating under the influence of reagents from spilled Nuka-Cola Quantum. Their fur emits a characteristic blue glow, and their bodies produce substances similar in composition to the famous drink.\n\nAlthough the creatures are quite dangerous due to high radiation levels, locals whisper that a tamed quantum rad deer could become a valuable acquisition. Rumors say their metabolism produces unique components that can be used to synthesize an analogue of Nuka-Cola Quantum. Some claim that a properly trained animal could even become a virtually inexhaustible source of raw materials for the legendary drink.\n\nCaution during encounters is mandatory - radiation significantly exceeds the norm, and the horned owners of such valuable resources are rarely friendly to strangers. However, for those who find an approach to these creatures, interesting prospects open up.</LetterGlowRadDeerPasses>

  <MysteriousInfectionLabel>Strange signal activated a sleeping agent</MysteriousInfectionLabel>
  <MysteriousInfection>It seems a threat was dormant right among you. {PAWN_nameDef}, one of your most inconspicuous settlers, receives an encrypted awakening signal from the surviving remnants of the Enclave.\n\nNow it's your decision: forcibly recruit a valuable agent with access to Old World secrets, or shackle them in handcuffs, neutralizing the threat and gaining a valuable slave.</MysteriousInfection>

  <LetterLabelEnclave>ATTENTION: Significant oil reserves detected in your colony!</LetterLabelEnclave>
  <EnclaveProtection>"RESPECTED COLONISTS!\n\nOur monitoring system has detected signs of:\n✓ Unregistered hydrocarbons\n✓ Insufficient democratization\n✓ Absence of freedom (by our definition)\n\nFOR YOUR OWN SAFETY we are sending:\n• A humanitarian mission (3 battalions)\n• Financial consultants (armed)\n• Democratic reforms (mandatory)\n• Do not resist - we come in peace*!\n• Peace may include tactical aviation and regime change"\n\nPS - "We'll have to confiscate your polymers so you don't waste them"</EnclaveProtection>

  <watcherLabel>"Watcher" didn't appreciate your joke</watcherLabel>
  <watcherText>You decided to play with fire - gave one of your settlers a name that doesn't belong to mortals. "Watcher". Just a set of sounds to you, but not to those who exist beyond your understanding.\n\nAt first it seemed like a harmless joke. The new colonist with a provocative name drew curious looks. But in a world where the laws of reality have thinned, names possess power. And some entities are extremely jealous of their uniqueness.\n\nYour attempt to appropriate this name didn't go unnoticed. You should prepare yourself...</watcherText>

  <!-- Titles -->
  <StrangeCall.Titles.Main>Intercepted Call</StrangeCall.Titles.Main>

  <!-- UPDATED RESPONSE OPTIONS -->
  <ContinueCrolling>Continue Trolling</ContinueCrolling>
  <Reset>Reset</Reset>

  <!-- Combined messages -->
  <StrangeCall.Messages.Threat0>Colonist - Well, here's the thing: we took your Navarro and found so much there... For example, indecent photos of your mother. Or were they your father's lace stockings? No wonder you're such a freak. Goodbye, asshole</StrangeCall.Messages.Threat0>
  <StrangeCall.Messages.Threat1>Communications Officer - Huh? Look how smart we are... Listen, buddy, I'm tracking you right now. Let's see how smart you are when internal security comes for your soul, cretin!</StrangeCall.Messages.Threat1>
  <StrangeCall.Messages.Threat2>Communications Officer - Well-well, my dear, just a couple more seconds - and I'll pinpoint you. Wait, what's this? It can't be... Are you on the mainland?!</StrangeCall.Messages.Threat2>
  <StrangeCall.Messages.Threat3>Communications Officer - Got you, there you are! Now sit still and don't go anywhere, I'm preparing a little celebration in your honor right now. With fireworks</StrangeCall.Messages.Threat3>
  <StrangeCall.Messages.EnclaveInfo>"Alarm sounds"</StrangeCall.Messages.EnclaveInfo>

  <!-- Warnings -->
  <StrangeCall.Warnings.RaidResponse>Trolling successful! {0} is sending a drop team to your position!</StrangeCall.Warnings.RaidResponse>
  <StrangeCall.Warnings.DropPodIncoming>Enemy drop pods detected! Prepare for attack!</StrangeCall.Warnings.DropPodIncoming>

  <ArmyCall.Titles.Main>Anonymous Call</ArmyCall.Titles.Main>

  <!-- Response options -->
  <ArmyCall.Answers.YesSir>YES Sir!</ArmyCall.Answers.YesSir>
  <ArmyCall.Answers.Mistake>Um... I think you have the wrong number</ArmyCall.Answers.Mistake>

  <!-- Main message -->
  <ArmyCall.Messages.Main>Sergeant Arch Dornan - So you're the new recruit, huh? YOU'RE OUT OF UNIFORM, SOLDIER! WHERE'S YOUR POWER ARMOR?! "Don't have any"? YOU EXPECT ME TO BELIEVE THAT, MAGGOT?! THE TRUTH IS YOU LOST EXPENSIVE ARMY EQUIPMENT! THAT SUIT IS GOING TO COME OUT OF YOUR PAY. AND YOU WILL REMAIN IN THIS ARMY UNTIL YOU ARE *gasps* 510 YEARS OLD, WHICH IS HOW LONG IT WILL TAKE FOR YOU TO PAY FOR THE MARK X-01 POWER ARMOR YOU HAVE LOST! REPORT TO THE ARMORY AND DRAW A NEW SUIT, THEN REPORT BACK TO ME, PRIVATE! DISMISSED!</ArmyCall.Messages.Main>

  <!-- Responses and messages -->
  <ArmyCall.Warnings.YesResponse>New power armor delivered to your location, private!</ArmyCall.Warnings.YesResponse>
  <ArmyCall.Warnings.TrapResponse>You're probably spies! Sound the alarm and finish this trash!</ArmyCall.Warnings.TrapResponse>
  <ArmyCall.Items.Received>Received: X-01 Power Armor and X-01 Helmet</ArmyCall.Items.Received>
  <ArmyCall.Items.FallbackReceived>Received backup power armor</ArmyCall.Items.FallbackReceived>
  <ArmyCall.Errors.SpawnFailed>Armor delivery error. Please try your request again later.</ArmyCall.Errors.SpawnFailed>
  
  
  <CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.label>Stench from the Depths</CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.label>
<CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.description>Something terrible is festering in the depths of the sewers...\n What is this horror?\n It's a Fecaloid!\n What?\n The Shit Demon!</CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.description>
<CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.letterLabel>Harbinger of Evil</CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.letterLabel>
<CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.letterText>Strange sounds are coming from the latrines. It seems something impure has awakened in the depths...\n What is this horror?\n It's a Fecaloid!\n What?\n The Shit Demon!</CreatureSpawnNearLatrine.letterText>
<CreatureSpawn.Warning.Title>Something Approaches from the Depths</CreatureSpawn.Warning.Title>
<CreatureSpawn.Warning.Text>Strange sounds echo from the foul depths of the sewers... Something impure has awakened and will soon emerge. Colonists report strange movements in the septic tanks and ominous gurgling. Prepare to face the unknown!\n What is this horror?\n It's a Fecaloid!\n What?\n The Shit Demon!</CreatureSpawn.Warning.Text>
<CreatureSpawn.Arrival.Title>Creature from the Depths!</CreatureSpawn.Arrival.Title>
<CreatureSpawn.Arrival.FromLatrine>A disgusting creature has burst forth from the foul sewer! It is covered in slime and radiates an unbearable stench. {0} attacks all living things!\n What is this horror?\n It's a Fecaloid!\n What?\n The Shit Demon!</CreatureSpawn.Arrival.FromLatrine>
<CreatureSpawn.Arrival.FromEdge>A mysterious creature has appeared at the edge of the map! {0}, covered in slime and stench, attacks the colony!\n What is this horror?\n It's a Fecaloid!\n What?\n The Shit Demon!</CreatureSpawn.Arrival.FromEdge>

<MoleRatQuarryAttack.label>Mole Rat Union</MoleRatQuarryAttack.label>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterLabel>Demands of the Mole Rat Union</MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterLabel>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterText>Work in the quarry has violated the sacred right of mole rats to eight hours of sleep during working hours! Representatives of the underground fauna union, numbering {0} individuals, have arrived for negotiations. Negotiations will be conducted from a position of strength, using claws and fury.</MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterText>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterTextExtended>EXTENDED NOTICE OF LABOR DISPUTE

The local mole rat union expresses extreme dissatisfaction with your excavation work.

Violations:
✓ Noise pollution (exceeding permissible digging levels)
✓ Vibrations (interfering with afternoon rest)
✓ Illegal mineral extraction (without deductions to the mole rat development fund)

Negotiators have been dispatched to resolve the conflict. Features of the negotiation process:
• Aggressive display of dissatisfaction
• Ankle biting
• Digging holes in pathways

It is recommended to immediately cease operations and offer compensation in the form of vegetables.</MoleRatQuarryAttack.letterTextExtended>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.laborDispute>LABOR DISPUTE WITH UNDERGROUND FAUNA</MoleRatQuarryAttack.laborDispute>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.mentalStateReason>violation of the underground fauna labor code</MoleRatQuarryAttack.mentalStateReason>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.unionRepresentative>Den Elder</MoleRatQuarryAttack.unionRepresentative>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.noise>Noise pollution (exceeding permissible digging levels)</MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.noise>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.vibration>Vibrations (interfering with afternoon rest)</MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.vibration>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.mining>Illegal mineral extraction (without deductions to the mole rat development fund)</MoleRatQuarryAttack.violation.mining>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.aggression>Aggressive display of dissatisfaction</MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.aggression>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.bites>Ankle biting</MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.bites>
<MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.digging>Digging holes in pathways</MoleRatQuarryAttack.negotiation.digging>

<MutantClan_FactionName>Mutant Clan</MutantClan_FactionName>
<MutantClanRaid_IncidentLabel>Mutant Clan Raid</MutantClanRaid_IncidentLabel>
<MutantClanRaid_LetterLabel>MEAT! GIVE MEAT!</MutantClanRaid_LetterLabel>
<MutantClanRaid_RaidText>ARGH! SMELLED IT! SMELLED THE SCENT OF MEAT FROM YOUR COLONY!

OUR TWISTED NOSTRILS TREMBLE FROM THE DELIGHTFUL AROMA OF HUMAN FLESH! MUCH MEAT! TOO MUCH FOR SUCH SMALL PEOPLE!

🦴 WHAT OUR WARPED MINDS SAY:
✓ MEAT: MUCH! WANT! NEED!
✓ BLOOD: FRESH! WARM! OURS!
✓ BONES: CRUNCHY! TASTY!

❗ ROAR OF THE BIG BOSS: WE WON'T TOLERATE COMPETITORS! YOUR MEAT IS OUR MEAT!

WE COME RUNNING TO YOU! RUN FAST! SCREAM LOUD! WE WILL BITE! TEAR! CHEW! DON'T RUN AWAY - TASTIER WHEN YOU'RE SCARED!

UGHHH! ARGHH! GRRR!
PACK "BONE-GNAWERS"
(WE ATE THE PREVIOUS TRIBE)</MutantClanRaid_RaidText>
<MutantClanLetter_LetterLabel>GIVE LITTLE PIECE! TAKE EVERYTHING!</MutantClanLetter_LetterLabel>
<MutantClanLetter_LetterText>HE-HE! HELLO, LITTLE MEAT SACKS!

WE SAW YOU PLAYING WITH FIRE AND MEAT! FUNNY! BUT YOU DO EVERYTHING WRONG! NO-NO!

OUR SCARRED TONGUES FEEL - SOMETHING'S MISSING FOR A TASTY FEAST BY THE FIRE!

HERE'S OUR KINDNESS! YOU CAN TRY! BUT NOT TOO MUCH - THE REST IS OURS!

TRY THROWING INTO THE FIRE AND SCREAMING! TASTIER THAT WAY! EVEN BETTER - RUNNING AROUND WITH A PIECE OF MEAT! WE LOVE THAT!

P.S. COMING SOON TO CHECK! PREPARE FOR HUGS! VERY STRONG HUGS!

SNORT-SNORT! YUM-YUM!
PACK "STINKY HUGGERS"
(HUG UNTIL BONES CRACK)</MutantClanLetter_LetterText>



</LanguageData>
