<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <Apparello_Vaultjumpsuit.label>Vault jumpsuit</Apparello_Vaultjumpsuit.label>
  <Apparello_Vaultjumpsuit.description>When the world turned into a radioactive hell, Vault-Tec made sure you had not just radiation protection, but fashionable radiation protection! The standard Vault Dweller jumpsuit is the perfect choice for those who prefer to face the nuclear winter with the iconic blue and yellow style and the signature smile of a gullible test subject.Made from a "revolutionary" alloy of cheap nylon and naive hope, this jumpsuit provides the illusion of safety, as well as convenient access for administering experimental drugs directly through the fabric.</Apparello_Vaultjumpsuit.description>

  <Apparello_VaultY-17trauma.label>Y-17 trauma override harness</Apparello_VaultY-17trauma.label>
  <Apparello_VaultY-17trauma.description>*"When you run out of ammo, your legs give way, and hope evaporates - don't worry! Your trusty 'Y-17 trauma override harness' already knows that you're a corpse. Or almost a corpse. In any case, it will do everything to drag your unconscious body to the nearest medical center... or at least to the place where it used to be!"*</Apparello_VaultY-17trauma.description>

  <Apparel_VaultY-17traumaHelmet.label>Y-17 Spacesuit helmet</Apparel_VaultY-17traumaHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_VaultY-17traumaHelmet.description>"Your face is our concern!(While it is still attached to the skull.)"</Apparel_VaultY-17traumaHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_VaultT60PowerArmor.label>T-60 power armor</Apparel_VaultT60PowerArmor.label>
  <Apparel_VaultT60PowerArmor.description>Developed in a hurry when it became clear that "good old T-51s were too expensive for our glorious post-war economy," the T-60 became the embodiment of the principle of "cheap, cheerful, and... well, at least it works."</Apparel_VaultT60PowerArmor.description>

  <Apparel_VaultT60ArmorHelmet.label>T-60 power Helmet</Apparel_VaultT60ArmorHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_VaultT60ArmorHelmet.description>*"Well, here's another 'lucky one' in this metal bucket! The T-60 helmet is the pinnacle of engineering, if, of course, you consider something heavy, stuffy and with a constant smell of burnt-out electronics to be the pinnacle. But what a view! You are a walking target, but a stylish one. The built-in HUD (if it still works) will kindly remind you that the armor is about to fall apart, and the filters are long overdue for replacement (if, of course, you find them in this mess called the post-war world).Special bonus: your neighbors in the Wasteland will immediately understand that you are either a big shot of the Brotherhood of Steel (and therefore, you have something to steal), or a looter who found the corpse of a big shot (and therefore, you still have something to steal). In any case, congratulations, now you will be punched in the face more often!P.S. Do not try to chew in a helmet. Seriously. You don't want to know what stew smells like after three days inside a closed helmet."**(Characteristics: +100% to pathos, +50% to visibility, -30% to olfactory receptors, 10% chance that you will be mistaken for a trash can and they will try to throw something at you.)*</Apparel_VaultT60ArmorHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_VaultX01PowerArmor.label>X-01 power armor</Apparel_VaultX01PowerArmor.label>
  <Apparel_VaultX01PowerArmor.description>Designed by the finest minds of pre-war America (who then fled to the vaults, abandoning everyone else to their fate), this armor is the embodiment of unstoppable might, unwavering ideology, and a complete disregard for common sense. Now you too can feel like an invincible Enclave soldier… until you realize that all your allies are either fanatics or corpses.</Apparel_VaultX01PowerArmor.description>

  <Apparel_VaultX01ArmorHelmet.label>X-01 power Helmet</Apparel_VaultX01ArmorHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_VaultX01ArmorHelmet.description>Forget the old world and its pathetic ideals. This helmet is more than just protection for your head, it's a symbol of your devotion to the Great Cause of the Enclave. Yes, it's uncomfortable, yes, the ventilation here is more theory than practice, and yes, it makes you look like a tin can with a complex of being the chosen one. But would a true patriot complain?The built-in voice module automatically replaces the words 'doubt', 'compassion' and 'humanity' with 'betrayal', 'weakness' and 'radiation chaos'. The 'Brainwash Mode' function is enabled by default - just inhale the government-approved fumes of lead and patriotism!Remember: if it becomes stuffy inside the spacesuit - it is not a lack of ventilation, it is your spirit burning too brightly for this rotten world. Glory to the Enclave!"(P.S. Long-term use may cause side effects: delusions of grandeur, hallucinations of a 'pure nation', and an overwhelming desire to shoot farmers in the name of democracy. The Enclave is not responsible for your war crimes. Well, it is, but we don't care.)</Apparel_VaultX01ArmorHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_VaultX01TeslaPowerArmor.label>X-01 Tesla power armor</Apparel_VaultX01TeslaPowerArmor.label>
  <Apparel_VaultX01TeslaPowerArmor.description>A modified version of the iconic X-01, designed by Enclave engineers in the best traditions of paranoia and over-weaponry. Its distinguishing feature is a magnetic force field that not only makes you look like a walking Pentagon experiment, but should also (theoretically) protect you from energy weapons.</Apparel_VaultX01TeslaPowerArmor.description>

  <Apparel_VaultT51ArmorHelmet.label>T-51 power Helmet</Apparel_VaultT51ArmorHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_VaultT51ArmorHelmet.description>*"Once the pinnacle of engineering, now just an expensive crutch for nostalgic soldiers and survivalists who still believe that "old is good." Yes, this helmet survived the Great War, but only because its previous owners either died before they could break it or were too dead to complain. Equipped with an air filtration system (if you're lucky), a built-in display (that twinkles like the lights on a pre-war Christmas tree), and a "bulletproof" visor (only tested on molerats running across a field), it comes with 200 years of dust, chipped paint, and the inexplicable smell of an old bunker. Recommended for collectors, masochists, and anyone who still believes that the United States of America, Inc., once cared about people."*</Apparel_VaultT51ArmorHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_VaultT51PowerArmor.label>T-51 power armor</Apparel_VaultT51PowerArmor.label>
  <Apparel_VaultT51PowerArmor.description>Once the pinnacle of pre-Kopf military thought, now it’s just walking scrap metal with nostalgic charm. The T-51 once inspired fear and respect, but now it looks more like a heated tin can with the smell of sweaty soldiers. Yes, it still has walls from radiation and bullets, but be prepared for the fact that every second bolt creaks, and the air filtration system considers cigarette smoke an “acceptable alternative to oxygen.” But it looks stylish — if your style is “nostalgia for the times when the world was not yet completely * @#%!”</Apparel_VaultT51PowerArmor.description>


</LanguageData>